Guide to the Cornell University concert and Sage Chapel programs, 1878-2015.
Cornell University concert and Sage Chapel programs, 1878-2017
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University concert and Sage Chapel programs, 1878-2017.
14-20-417
Cornell University.
6.6 cubic feet
Programs, correspondence, brochures, publications, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Programs of concerts and recitals at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection contains programs of concerts and recitals by Cornell and non-Cornell groups that took place at Cornell University. Cornell groups represented in the collection include the Wind Symphony, Chorus, Chamber Orchestra, Symphony Orchestra, Contemporary Chamber Players, Percussion Ensemble, Wind Ensemble, Cornell Jazz Festival, Cornell Glee Club and others. Also programs for Cornell United Religious Works and Sage Chapel events and services such as organ recitals and vespers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Bailey Hall (Cornell University); Cornell University. Concert Band.; Cornell University. Festival of Contemporary Arts.; Cornell University Orchestra.; Cornell University. Symphonic Band.; Sage Chapel (Cornell University); Willard Straight Hall (Ithaca, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Concert programs--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Music.
Form and Genre Terms:
Programs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Cornell University Dept. of Music records, #14-20-513
Cornell University Music Library records, #13-7-2584
Welsey Barnet Carroll music programs, #37-5-1989
Cornell University Chorus records, #14-20-3125
Cornell University Glee Club records, #37-6-2399
Sage Chapel programs, #39-5-371
Elizabeth Lyman theater and concert programs, #2239
NOTES
Includes collection #14-20-353.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Sage Chapel Materials
  - Sage Chapel programs (bound), 1923-1967 (Box 1)
  - Sage Chapel organ recitals (bound), 1913-1933 (Box 1)
  - Sage Chapel organ recitals, 1884-1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Summer Session musical recitals, 1903-1908 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sage Chapel services, 1929-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sage Chapel Christmas programs, 1944-2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sage Chapel centennial programs, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sage Chapel miscellaneous, 1878-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series II: Cornell University Musical Events Calendars and Programs
  - Cornell University concert programs (bound), 1934-1972 (Box 3)
  - Cornell University concert programs, 1880-September 1994 (Box 4)
  - Cornell University concert programs, 1994-2012, undated; 33 folders (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1928-2004, undated; 1 folder (Box 5)
  - Contemporary Music Festival programs, 1968-1979; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Contemporary Music Festival programs, 1992-2008; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Series III: Cornell University Musical Events Programs, Promotional Materials, and Correspondence
  - Summer concerts, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Personnel office, 1944-1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Artists' programs, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Publicity and advertisitng, Bailey Hall series, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Artists' programs, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Rochester Civic Music Association, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Yves Tinayre, April 19, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - M. Anderson, Fall 1946 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Baltimore Symphony Orchestra, Fall 1946 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Rochester Philharmonic, December 2, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - G. Enesco, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Concert schedule, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Columbia concerts, Bidu Sayao, February 1947 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Mack Harrell, March 1947 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - President Day, March 1947 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Muriel Kerr, March 1947 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Gala benefit, April 2, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The Stuyvesant String Quartet, November 1947 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Yves Tinayre, November 1947 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The Walden String Quartet, December 1947 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Last page of Bailey programs, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - A. Brailowsky, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cleveland Orchestra, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Emanuel Vardi, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Rochester Civic Music Association, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Chamber music, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - The Bach Aria Group, January 1948 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Sophomore benefit, March 1948 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Pascal String Quartet, March 1948 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - The Busch String Quartet, March 1948 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Maynor, October 1948 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - London String Quartet, November 2, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - N.Y. Woodwind Ensemble, November 9, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Rochester Philharmonic Orchestra, November 1948 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - A. Schneider, R. Kirkpatrick, November 1948 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Chamber music - general, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Griller String Quartet, January 20, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Morini, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Whittemore and Lowe, February 1949 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, February 1949 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - John Kirkpatrick, March 1, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Budapest String Quartet, March 1949 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Juilliard String Quartet, March 15, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Shaw Chorale, March 1949 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Walden String Quartet, May 3, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Pro Musica Antiqus, October 1949 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Walden String Quartet, November 29, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Buffalo Philharmonic, December 1949 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Elena Nikoladi, December 12, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Jussi Bjoerling, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Chamber music - general, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Modern Art Quartet, January 6, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Benno Moiseiwitsh, January 1950 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Cleveland Orchestra, February 1950 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Stuyvesant String Quartet, February 14, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Isaac Stern, February 1950 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - London String Quartet, March 12, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Rochester Civic, April 1950 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Zino Francescatti, October 17, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Jacqueline Blancard and Andre de Ribaupierre, November 7, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Hungarian Quartet, December 5, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Bach Festival, November 1950 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - The Little Orchestra, November 28, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Chamber music - general, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Rudolf Surkin, January 1951 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Budapest String Quartet, January 8, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra, January 22, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Woodwind Quartet, February 2, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Andres Segovia, February 27, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Shaw Chorale, March 1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Haydn's Creation, March 21, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Walden String Quartet, April 17, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Festival of Contemporary Arts - chamber music concert, April 20, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Eileen Farrell, October 9, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Randolf Singers, November 5, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra, November 6, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rudolf Firkusny, December 4, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Chamber music - general, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - New Friends of Music Quartet, January 7, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Joseph Fuchs, January 15, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Hungarian Quartet, February 5, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cleveland Orchestra, February 15, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Luigi Silva, February 26, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Mozart Chamber Orchestra, March 11, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Walden String Quartet, April 22, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Special spring concert, Bailey Hall, May 16, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Summer Session, Aug. 1952 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Quartetto Italiano (cancelled), November 4, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Danish State Orchestra, November 17, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Juilliard String Quartet, December 2, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - William Warfield, December 16, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Chamber music - general, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Griller String Quartet, January 6, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Hungarian Quartet, January 13, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Isaac Stern, January 20, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Cleveland Orchestra, February 13, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Pasquier Trio, February 24, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Shaw Chorale, March 16, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Myra Hess (cancelled), April 21, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - A. Brailowsky, April 21, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Sunday afternoon concerts, May 1953 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Chamber music, A/C completed (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Quartetto Italiano, October 6, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Pro Musica Antiqua, October 20, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, October 25, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Yehudi Menuhin, November 10, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Fall Term - free concerts, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Chamber music - general, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Jennie Tourel, January 12, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Cleveland Orchestra, February 19, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Hungarian Quartet, Mar. 2, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Rochester Philharmonic, Mar. 12, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Rudolf Surkin, Mar. 21, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Walden String Quartet, April 13, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Contemporary Arts Festival, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Concertgebouw Orchestra, October 17, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, November 9, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Concert Choir, November 16, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Quartetto Italiano, November 30, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Boris Goldovsky's Opera Theater, December 9, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chamber music - general, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Chamber music - financial, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bailey Hall - general, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Claudio Arrau, January 14, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Mannes-Gimpel-Silva Trio, January 18, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Cleveland Orchestra, February 18, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Szigeti and American Chamber Orchestra, March 8, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Valenti-Baker-Ricci Trio, March 14, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Juilliard String Quartet, April 7, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Fall Term - free concerts, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Pictures, February 25, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - B-Minor Mass, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - 648 - University Concerts - completed, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Bailey Hall organ, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Spring - special concerts, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Concert programs, Small case (Box 8)
    Includes 1906, 1908-1910, 1914-1916 and 1920
  - Concert programs (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
    Includes 1961/1962 - 1968/1969
  - Concert programs, Fall 2008 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Concert programs, Spring 2009 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Concert programs, Fall 2009 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Concert programs, Spring 2010 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Programs, July-December 2012 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Programs, Spring 2013 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Programs, Fall 2013 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Programs, Spring 2014 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Programs, Fall 2014 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Programs, Spring 2015 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Music department programs, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 11)